<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Make money while you work</title>
 <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-01-12T03:59:46+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Leo Treasure</name>
   <email>leotreasure@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Using alt coins to mix bitcoins</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2016/01/11/using-alt-coins-to-mix-bitcoins/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2016/01/11/using-alt-coins-to-mix-bitcoins</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering why mixing bitcoins is important you should read the following link
https://bitcoin.org/en/protect-your-privacy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t have time all you need to know about Bitcoin and Privacy is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Anyone can see the balance and all transactions of any address&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering, why use an alternative coin to mix bitcoins when you can just use bitcoins?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Bitcoin’s blockchain is able to be analysed more easily by anyone with access to blockchain analysis tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.walletexplorer.com/&quot;&gt;Wallet Explorer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinalytics.co/&quot;&gt;Coinalytics&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quantabytes.com/&quot;&gt;QuantaBytes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while there are many ways to mix bitcoins, I wanted to compare two alternative coins that are touted to make your transaction activity private and untraceable; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dash.org/&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org/home&quot;&gt;Monero&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-goal-was-to-mix-the-relatively-small-sum-of-002-bitcoins-just-under-10-usd-worth&quot;&gt;My goal was to mix the relatively small sum of 0.02 bitcoins (just under $10 USD worth)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy the alt coin with Bitcoin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the alt coin’s mixing function&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sell the alt coin back for Bitcoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;results-table&quot;&gt;Results table&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;XBT&lt;/strong&gt; = Bitcoin
&lt;strong&gt;XMR&lt;/strong&gt; = Monero&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monero&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sync blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;~ 2 – 24 hours&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;~ 1 – 2 hours&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protocol confirmation time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;~ 1 minute&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;~ 2 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.02 XBT bought:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18.2033312&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.91&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price of alternative coin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0010987 XBT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.00673189 DASH&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Withdrawal fee (Poloniex)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.2 XMR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.05 DASH&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coin amount after withdrawal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18.0033312&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.86&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimum mixing amount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;None&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.49 DASH&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum mixing amount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 bitcoin if using xmr.to&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;limited to 1000 DASH per session&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requires multiple sessions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes, for large amounts and when ‘Dark Sending’&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixing transaction fees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.105 XMR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Unable to ascertain&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixing time including blocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9 minutes 50 seconds&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Didn’t complete&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy back XBT price&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.001063&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.00696206&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total fees as a percentage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.942 %&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total XBT after Mixing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0191735&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NB.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;‘Total fees as a percentage’&lt;/em&gt; may seem a bit off because I paid the mixing transaction fee from additional Monero funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-to-mix&quot;&gt;Time to mix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With alt coin prices being volatile, the time it takes to mix is a critical factor to consider when transferring out of and back into Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dash&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dash’s mixing system is currently called &lt;em&gt;Dark Send&lt;/em&gt;. For a detailed overview &lt;a href=&quot;https://dashpay.atlassian.net/wiki/display/DOC/Introduction+To+Darksend&quot;&gt;read the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick description of the process is you press the &lt;em&gt;‘Start Darksend Mixing’&lt;/em&gt; button and this is like a premixing step. Every &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; blocks &lt;em&gt;Master Nodes&lt;/em&gt; mix your coins and break them down into homogenous denominations, giving you back other people’s (or liquidity providers) mixed coins of the same denominations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The catch is though that the process has a percentage status bar and if it doesn’t reach 100% then the mix is tainted with your original coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I wanted to do this experiment with only 0.01 bitcoin, but as I found out the hard way - Dash has a minimum threshold requirement of 1.49 Dash (and my 0.01 bitcoin only got me 1.43!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I only counted one of the withdrawal fees in the Dash column&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 4 hours and 5 minutes of mixing with Dash I realised it was 6am and should probably get some sleep. It was at 84% and I clicked ‘Stop Darksend Mixing’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The reason I stopped the mixing process is because I wanted to accurately time how long the mix took and be there to stop the timer when it reached 100%.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, I clicked ‘Start Darksend Mixing’ – at this stage the completion box showed 90%. After waiting another 70 minutes the completion box still showed 90%. I ran out of patience at this point and concluded the coins were stuck as a result of interrupting the mixing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Darksend Balance showed that I had 2.4 Dash with some dust available to spend. So I try to Dark Send my 2.4, but got this error:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/unableToAnonymise.png&quot; alt=&quot;errorMsgUnableToAnonymise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick read of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dashtalk.org/forums/darksend-questions-and-help.77/&quot;&gt;Dash support forum section on dark send&lt;/a&gt; shows I’m not alone with my struggle to mix Dash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave up trying to anonymously send Dash because I thought Dark Sending again would take another 5 hours on top of the time for debugging the stuck coins issue. It turns out though, you only have to wait for the initial premixing to complete 100% once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, debugging the stuck coins issue not knowing whether or not I’d need to wait another 5 hours to 100% complete the premix was not an appealing prospect so I sent the coins back only 90% mixed to the exchange (thus destroying any anonymity those coins would have gained).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creator of Dash is working on changing the way Dark Send works ‘a bit’ by removing the mixing role from the Master Nodes. Just as well because Dark Send in its current state didn’t work at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps if I hadn’t interrupted the mixing process, it may have worked. But the inability to pause a Dark Send seems like a pretty major bug to me. What if you were mixing coins at a public location on a laptop and you had to close the lid for a few minutes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, even if it had worked, waiting ~ 5 hours to mix under $10 worth of bitcoins doesn’t feel like the future of untraceable digital cash..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monero&quot;&gt;Monero&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monero mixes instantly by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org/knowledge-base/moneropedia/ringsignatures&quot;&gt;ring signatures&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org/knowledge-base/moneropedia/stealthaddress&quot;&gt;stealth addresses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A ring signature is a group of cryptographic signatures with at least one real participant, but there is no way to tell which in the group is the real one as they all appear valid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stealth addresses let the recipient publish just one address, yet have all of his/her incoming payments go to unique addresses on the blockchain, where they cannot be linked back to either the recipient’s published address or any other transactions’ addresses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poloniex doesn’t let you mix Monero from their wallet, so I used two other Monero wallet/exchange services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mymonero.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mymonero.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mymonero&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MyMonero is a wallet that let me send the coins with a configurable privacy level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xmr.to&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/xmrto.png&quot; alt=&quot;xmr.to&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; XMR.TO is a one-way Monero to Bitcoin exchange which I used to buy back the bitcoins with the &lt;em&gt;moneroj&lt;/em&gt; (term for Monero coins) I bought from &lt;a href=&quot;https://poloniex.com&quot;&gt;Poloniex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org/home&quot;&gt;Monero&lt;/a&gt; is the clear winner with its no minimum, hassle free and ultra-fast mixing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind though that it’s generally a good idea to wait some random amount of time when you mix to prevent attackers correlating your transactions with &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/is-bitcoin-anonymous-a-complete-beginner-s-guide-1447875283&quot;&gt;timing analysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Importance of Anonymous Money</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/17/the-importance-of-anonymous-money/"/>
   <updated>2015-12-17T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/17/the-importance-of-anonymous-money</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-cash-were-banned&quot;&gt;If cash were banned…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/wallet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallet with only credit cards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where all transactions were between known and identified parties, cash replaced by banking products that followed ‘Know Your Customer’ procedures diligently. The argument for this utopia goes that there’d be much less crime in general, less fraud, tax evasion, illicit drugs &amp;amp; other illegal acts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;less-crime-or-more&quot;&gt;Less crime, or more?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we required every transaction to be detailed with the nature and purpose, along with the identities to reduce crime, it may save lives - but at what cost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regulations around knowing your customer currently only apply to financial services businesses because they deal with large amounts of money. If every bank checked what the purpose was for every transaction (large or small), people would get silly questions about their shopping activities for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘You bought this tablet just for yourself?’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Yes.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Okay, make sure to register any family members or friends who do any online shopping on it with us.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This example is kind of exaggerated and I hope it never gets anywhere close to this but it shows how complete knowledge of a customer’s activities might engender a mutual distrust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you bought bitcoins before?&lt;/strong&gt;
In case you haven’t experienced buying bitcoins yet, try using your bank account and see if you receive a phone call from your bank inquiring about the reason why you are buying them. You can tell them you were just trying it to see if they would check up on your transactions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;less-fraud-because-banks-have-everything-under-control&quot;&gt;Less fraud (because banks have everything under control)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was scammed buying a phone on the Internet I thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everything will be okay, my bank has a fraud department and a money back guarantee! I remember from the TV advert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But banks have a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different definition of fraud to what most consumers have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consumer, you expect that when someone uses their bank account to scam you - banks will act to protect you. Here is the catch of bank’s fraud protection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You didn’t contribute to the loss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you send money to a bank account, that is contributing to the loss and there is no protection for that loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world without cash and more dependability on banking services, I expect there’d be the same level or more fraud because scammers will spend their ill gotten gains ASAP anyway, leaving a merchant somewhere at a loss if the transaction is reversed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-tax-collected&quot;&gt;More tax collected&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everyone was forced to use a government monitored stored value account, nobody could possible avoid paying tax. This is just a recipe for disaster. Paying tax not only supports schools, hospitals and police - it also supports political corruption, corporations (who usually don’t pay tax anyway), propaganda, cronyism, inequality and most disgustingly, large scale wars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are much better ways to support schools, hospitals and police than collecting taxes, one idea is to actually give them money, voluntarily! Relying on subsidies is an unworkable and corruptible practice that needs to cease now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;illicit-drugs&quot;&gt;Illicit drugs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The war on drugs has to be one of the most successful government propaganda stories ever told. Not only was the most popular drug at the time;marijuana, made illegal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drugwarrant.com/articles/why-is-marijuana-illegal/&quot;&gt;without due process&lt;/a&gt; - it has very many &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/health-benefits-of-medical-marijuana-2014-4?op=1&quot;&gt;medicinal benefits&lt;/a&gt; when used in moderation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are many other illicit drugs that can also have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/03/04/health/lsd-reconsidered-for-therapy.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;psychological health benefits too&lt;/a&gt; when used in moderation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-illegal-acts&quot;&gt;Other illegal acts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take away peoples’ privacy, control, money and drugs - it really is the best recipe to encourage them to commit other illegal acts to fight ‘the system’. The government should treat its citizens like with maturity and respect and not distrust and contempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;isnt-bitcoin-anonymous&quot;&gt;Isn’t Bitcoin anonymous?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitcoinisnotanonymous.com&quot;&gt;bitcoinisnotanonymous.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Getting started with crypto-currency</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/08/getting-started-with-crypto-currency/"/>
   <updated>2015-12-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/08/getting-started-with-crypto-currency</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-following-post-is-a-guest-post-by-a-pseudo-anonymous-contributor-jackson1442&quot;&gt;The following post is a guest post by a pseudo-anonymous contributor: jackson1442&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitcoin---a-brief-background&quot;&gt;Bitcoin - A Brief Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people have heard of Bitcoin, yet not many people know what it really is or how to use it.
Bitcoin is a crypto-currency – a currency that exists online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many people the main attracting feature of Bitcoin is that it can be somewhat anonymous. Since most desktop Bitcoin wallets don’t require registration, very few people can trace your transactions back to you. You can also create as many addresses as you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin can’t be counterfeited. All Bitcoin transactions are logged in the Blockchain, which is viewable by anyone. The Blockchain shows how much Bitcoin was sent to each address and who sent it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you send bitcoins to someone, the miners (computers running software that validates transactions) validate that you have control over the bitcoins that you’re sending and that the bitcoins you’re sending exist. With all of these components, you have a pretty solid foundation for a currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin has real-world applications, too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wagecan.com&quot;&gt;Some companies&lt;/a&gt; have made Bitcoin debit cards that draws from your Bitcoin wallet and converts your bitcoins to spendable cash. Some businesses have started to accept Bitcoin by having customers scan QR codes with their wallet apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alternative-coins&quot;&gt;Alternative coins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the alternative coins come in to play. So many people saw that Bitcoin was growing and they wanted their share. Alt-coins are coins (typically forks of Bitcoin) that are different from bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter Monero. Monero is an alt-coin that is based on privacy. Transactions are piled together with other people’s transactions, which makes it both unlinkable and untraceable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin, people are encouraged to make a new Bitcoin address for each transaction which makes their transactions more difficult to link. However, most people using Bitcoin don’t do this and in fact reuse the same address for many different payments. This makes Bitcoin much easier to link identities and trace payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who follow the recommended practice of making a new address for each payment can still have their transactions traced when they spend bitcoins from the same wallet that contain multiple addresses, all addresses are used simultaneously and a strong link can be established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Untraceable means that even the recipient has no idea where the payment came from. Monero piles many different transactions together automatically, making them untraceable. Nobody knows who you’re sending coins to and how many coins are in any one person’s address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-in-crypto-currency&quot;&gt;Getting Started in Crypto-Currency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what Bitcoin is and how it works, we can get started.
There are several ways to get coins, here are the main ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buying them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mining for them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hitting up the Bitcoin faucets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buying&quot;&gt;Buying&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the simplest option you’ve got. There are several places to buy from, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/join/leotreasure&quot;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; being my favorite. They have a special deal where if you click that link and buy $100 of bitcoins, you get an extra 10%! Coinbase is also a wallet (also my personal favorite, there’s no fees). The Bitcoin market changes on a day to day basis, so I recommend buying while the Bitcoin market is weak. That’s the easiest option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mining&quot;&gt;Mining&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most complicated option there is. At this point, Bitcoin is so difficult to mine, you’ll need a “mining rig” to get anything. (Mining rigs are computers made custom just for mining cryptocurrencies.) I won’t get too in depth with this. Basically, miners solve difficult algorithms while validating transactions. If you want to mine, just search for ‘Bitcoin mining pools’ and looks for directions, because each pool has different recommendations for setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fauceteering&quot;&gt;Fauceteering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own made up word for what I do &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;. There are many, many websites out there that display an amazing amount of ads (so many that you can’t believe how there’s room for anything else), and in exchange for going to that site, you get free bitcoins. Not much, but it adds up (eventually). This is how I got started, and how I recommend you get started. You can find my personally approved list of faucets here. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writeurl.com/text/dnrcaa6a1w3q3bvbd4bu/81g4zd4spcs4mutrq5rv&quot;&gt;List of faucets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gambling&quot;&gt;Gambling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kind of frowned upon way. I personally don’t like this method. This wasn’t included in the main ways to get Bitcoin for a reason. There are sites that you can spend Bitcoin and play a hi-low game, sometimes winning a ton of money, sometimes losing a ton of money. To find Bitcoin gambling sites just go to a faucet, you’ll find tons of ads for them. Or of course there are also gambling sites specifically for Monero, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://monerodice.net&quot;&gt;MoneroDice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://safedice.com&quot;&gt;SafeDice&lt;/a&gt;. Please use them at your own risk and don’t lose all of your money to a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-monero&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Monero&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to get started with Monero. There aren’t many faucets yet, so you’re pretty much limited to either buying or mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buying-monero&quot;&gt;Buying Monero&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You aren’t really going to find many places to buy Monero for cash. The easiest way to get some Monero is to first buy some of (almost) any cryptocurrency, most likely Bitcoin or Litecoin. Then, you go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://shapeshift.io&quot;&gt;shapeshift.io&lt;/a&gt;. ShapeShift is a website that will convert (almost) any cryptocurrency, with no account required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mining-monero&quot;&gt;Mining Monero&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mining Monero isn’t &lt;em&gt;nearly&lt;/em&gt; as hard as mining Bitcoin, but is still a complicated process. With Monero, you can use a personal computer to mine still, but you won’t get as fast as dedicated mining rigs out there. Personally, I suggest using the Yam client with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://moneropool.com/&quot;&gt;MoneroPool&lt;/a&gt; mining pool. &lt;a href=&quot;https://moneropool.com/#getting_started&quot;&gt;Instructions for download and setup are on their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monero isn’t a very big currency… yet. I think it’s a really cool concept, it just needs to be used. So, please, by all means, start using Monero. It’s great for privacy conscious people who want to stay safe on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: monero.org is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the official Monero website. &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org&quot;&gt;getmonero.org&lt;/a&gt; is the official website!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, crypto-currencies are a great investment and whichever one you choose to use, you’ll have money to spend online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-
Jackson1442&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Monero Experience</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/05/monero-experience-01/"/>
   <updated>2015-12-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/05/monero-experience-01</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-following-post-is-a-guest-post-by-an-anonymous-contributor&quot;&gt;The following post is a guest post by an anonymous contributor&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-monero-xmr-is-easy&quot;&gt;Using Monero (XMR) is easy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-monero-is&quot;&gt;What Monero is&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monero is a digital crypto-currency based on Crypto-note technology. Monero is a safe transaction based currency with some special features such as a payment address and a payment ID. The Crypto-note is the basis on how this currency is mined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-experience&quot;&gt;My experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience with Monero (XMR) was really a positive one knowing that this type of digital currency had not only a payment address, but also a payment ID. This was easy for me to understand since it was a direct comparison to any normal bank account with a transit number and an account number. The one thing that was a great security was in order to use a digital currency exchange web site, you would have to enter both the payment address, and the payment ID to be sure only you received the Monero.  Using Monero (XMR) was very easy, as is using any of the other Digital Currencies, with one exception, Monero is a more secure transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monero digital currency is valued at approximately $0.38 USD. At present, Monero can be used in the entertainment of online casinos. Hopefully, in the future, there will be more markets to spend Monero so there is less fees in exchanging Monero to another currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was to download the Monero Digital Wallet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org&quot;&gt;getmonero.org&lt;/a&gt;.  Downloading the wallet and installing was simple, as I have used many digital currencies to date.  The setup program for the digital wallet was simple, and really did not take that much thought to install for me.  After I have set up the wallet, which was easy, the next step was to get the right program to start mining Monero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mining-for-monero&quot;&gt;Mining For Monero.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MoneroExperience01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Minergate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mining Monero I found to be very easy, with no confusing codes or .bat files to type. The easiest program I found was Minergate. Minergate can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minergate.com&quot;&gt;www.minergate.com&lt;/a&gt;. This program allowed me to use my two computers with quad four processors (4 CPU cores). Using Minergate allowed me to mine Monero as well as a bonus coin on one computer, as well as mining Bytecoin (BCN) and the bonus coin on the second one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Minergate program has a built in wallet to store the Monero and other coins mined, this makes it easier to send the coins in bulk to your wallet or exchange web site. It has been my experience that depending on what type of computer you have, or if you are CPU mining or GPU mining, makes a difference on how long it will take to get results. Even though I was CPU mining I did have results fast. The Monero was partial coins, but that was not really bad, since after only a week I had a few thousand Bytecoins (BCN) that I send to a web based exchange and exchanged them for Monero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Bytecoin came in very fast and more frequently I opened up an exchange site at &lt;a href=&quot;https://poloniex.com&quot;&gt;poloniex.com&lt;/a&gt;. This allowed me to send my Bytecoins to the exchange and trade them for Monero very quickly. I did not have any long delays and the Monero was in my Poloniex account within minutes. Monero is also a very easy currency to use, because it is able to be traded to many other currencies rapidly as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-to-be-aware-of&quot;&gt;Things to be aware of&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like any other site that you want information on always be sure to go to the official sites. With Monero the official site is &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org&quot;&gt;getmonero.org&lt;/a&gt;. Do not use any other site that looks similar, you will only be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum it up Monero can be obtained through mining and can be used to play in a few entertainment online casino sites. I have found that trading Monero is by far easier than you think. I have had an easy time mining and using Monero.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Monero Addresses Infographic</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/04/monero-addresses-infographic/"/>
   <updated>2015-12-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/04/monero-addresses-infographic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;piktowrapper-embed&quot; pikto-uid=&quot;9821437-why-monero-addresses-are-so-obscenely-long&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;pikto-canvas-wrap&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;pikto-canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    (function(d){
        var js, id=&quot;pikto-embed-js&quot;, ref=d.getElementsByTagName(&quot;script&quot;)[0];
        if (d.getElementById(id)) { return;}
        js=d.createElement(&quot;script&quot;); js.id=id; js.async=true;
        js.src=&quot;https://magic.piktochart.com/assets/embedding/embed.js&quot;;
        ref.parentNode.insertBefore(js, ref);
    }(document));
&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Monero Infographic</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/03/monero-infographic/"/>
   <updated>2015-12-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/03/monero-infographic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;piktowrapper-embed&quot; pikto-uid=&quot;9886574-monero-infographic-updated&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;pikto-canvas-wrap&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;pikto-canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    (function(d){
        var js, id=&quot;pikto-embed-js&quot;, ref=d.getElementsByTagName(&quot;script&quot;)[0];
        if (d.getElementById(id)) { return;}
        js=d.createElement(&quot;script&quot;); js.id=id; js.async=true;
        js.src=&quot;https://magic.piktochart.com/assets/embedding/embed.js&quot;;
        ref.parentNode.insertBefore(js, ref);
    }(document));
&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Monero</title>
   <link href="http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/01/introducing-monero/"/>
   <updated>2015-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://makemoneywhileyouwork.com/2015/12/01/introducing-monero</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A private crypto-currency with amazing fungibility and protocol level mixing&lt;/em&gt; just about sums up the relatively new crypto-currency; Monero, created in April 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crypto-currency-adoption&quot;&gt;Crypto-currency adoption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many people have heard of Bitcoin, (and some of those have heard of Dogecoin or Litecoin) most people have never heard of Monero. Some people complain about missing the Bitcoin boat. I personally don’t think that boat has sailed yet (though there’d be many who’d disagree). You’re here reading about Monero before it’s in the news so if you buy some at these price levels you’ll be an early adopter. I do think Monero is going to be a hot topic in world news due to its high degree of decentralisation and anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a liberating tool and extremely interesting social experiment in money. However, there are some difficulties using it as a medium of exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full traceability is bad news for proprietary businesses (competitors can glean information using blockchain analysis).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncertainty over block size consensus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People explicitly seeking privacy usually mix coins, losing value in fees or fraud.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poor fungibility - exchanges can confiscate your bitcoins if they suspect they were involved in criminal transactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Bitcoin, Monero has a similar amount in total supply (18.4 million) of which around 10.2 million are already generated. It’s worth pointing out that Monero’s supply differs to Bitcoin because it has continual inflation (less than 1% per year) when the 18.4 million mark is reached (2022).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another small difference is that Monero’s reward is smoothly varying with the difficulty retargeting at every block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Bitcoin however, Monero is not traceable by default and block size is dynamically adjusted. The details of how this works exactly will be the subject of another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;centralisation&quot;&gt;Centralisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is mined these days mostly by large companies - the majority of which are mining in China because of the cheap electricity, access to mining equipment and proximity to fabrication houses (Taiwan). This is disconcerting when Satoshi’s original vision was to have a &lt;em&gt;decentralised, peer to peer digital cash system&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/building.png&quot; alt=&quot;building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Monero it is not only &lt;abbr title=&quot;Application Specific Integrated Circuit&quot;&gt;ASIC&lt;/abbr&gt; resistant, but also &lt;abbr title=&quot;Graphics Processing Unit&quot;&gt;GPU&lt;/abbr&gt; resistant too - meaning people with ordinary computers can participate in securing the network and be rewarded for doing so. Solo mining is even available - with the reward at around 7.8 &lt;abbr title=&quot;crypto-currency unit code for Monero&quot;&gt;XMR&lt;/abbr&gt; (around $2.92 USD) don’t expect to hit the jackpot anytime soon. The difficulty right now is high enough that an ordinary computer would only find a block once every 3 months. However, in the future it could be worth many multiples if Monero follows a similar trajectory that Bitcoin once did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-i-make-money-with-monero&quot;&gt;How can I make money with Monero?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back over the last few years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/oct/29/bitcoin-forgotten-currency-norway-oslo-home&quot;&gt;some people made an absolute fortune&lt;/a&gt; with Bitcoin &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/blog/2013/jul/01/bitcoin-virtual-fortune-crypto-currency&quot;&gt;simply mining&lt;/a&gt; or buying small amounts if it when it was worth next to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History tends to repeat itself. Early investors in the crypto-currency space are well positioned in the events of the global economy faltering, a bank collapsing, a stock market crash or even if none of the above happens and Internet trade just increases. Monero is worth around 37.5 cents at the time of writing. If more people value private digital cash in the future the value will increase - how much it increases by is anyone’s guess! Monero holds a number of advantages over Bitcoin and as more people discover this, its market value should increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;The rabbit hole…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head to the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmonero.org/&quot;&gt;Monero website&lt;/a&gt; for more information on Monero. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.getmonero.org/&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;, sign up for a web wallet with &lt;a href=&quot;https://mymonero.com/&quot;&gt;MyMonero&lt;/a&gt; and buy your first moneros (&lt;abbr title=&quot;crypto-currency unit code for Monero&quot;&gt;XMR&lt;/abbr&gt;) using &lt;a href=&quot;https://poloniex.com/exchange#btc_xmr&quot;&gt;Poloniex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you happen to be using Chrome there’s a cool extension called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/monero-monitor/ojekadcfnkkihlleaafggfgbggdckpgo/related&quot;&gt;Monero Monitor&lt;/a&gt; that gives you up to date information of Monero.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
